<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc id="P13-1062" editor="B" format="Conf" position="S" region="NN">
    <title>
        <text>Bootstrapping Entity Translation on Weakly Comparable Corpora</text>
    </title>
    <abstract>
        <text>This paper studies the problem of mining named entity translations from comparable corpora with some “asymmetry</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr=",”" comments="">”.</edit>
        <text>Unlike</text>
        <edit type="conciseness" crr="" comments="">the</edit>
        <text>previous approaches</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="that rely" comments="">relying</edit>
        <text>on the “symmetry” found in parallel corpora, the proposed method is tolerant to</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="the" comments=""></edit>
        <text>asymmetry often found in comparable corpora</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="," comments=""></edit>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="because it distinguishes" comments="">by distinguishing</edit>
        <text>different semantics of relations of entity pairs to selectively propagate seed entity translations on weakly comparable corpora. Our experimental results on English-Chinese corpora show that our selective propagation approach outperforms</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="the" comments=""></edit>
        <text>previous approaches in named entity translation</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr=", improving" comments="">in terms of</edit>
        <text> the mean reciprocal rank by up to 0.16 for organization names</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="">,</edit>
        <text>and 0.14 in a low comparability case.</text>
    </abstract>   
    <introduction>
        <text>Identifying and understanding entities is a crucial step in understanding text. This task is more challenging in the presence of multilingual text</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="">,</edit>
        <text>because translating named entities (NEs), such as</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="people" comments="">persons</edit>
        <text>, locations, or organizations, is a non-trivial task. Early research on NE translation used phonetic similarities, for example, to mine the translation ‘Mandelson’→‘曼德尔森’[ManDeErSen] with similar sounds. However, not all NE translations are based on transliterations, as shown in Table 1</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="." comments="">—</edit>
        <text>Some translations, especially the names of most organizations, are based on semantic equivalences.</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="In addition" comments="">Furthermore</edit>
        <text>, names can be abbreviated in one or both languages, e.g., the ‘World Trade Organization’ (世界贸易组织)</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="may also" comments="">can</edit>
        <text>be called the ‘WTO’ (世贸组织). Another challenging</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="example" comments="">factor</edit>
        <text>is that</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="translations" comments="">, a translation</edit>
        <text>can be arbitrary, e.g., ‘Jackie Chan’ → ‘成龙’ [ChengLong].</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="Researchers have proposed approaches to address" comments="">There are many approaches that deel with</edit>
        <text>some of these challenges (Lam et al., 2007; Yang et al., 2009),</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="for example, proposed" comments="">e.g., by</edit>
        <text>combining phonetic similarity and a dictionary. However, arbitrary translations still cannot be handled by examining the NE pair itself. Corpus-based approaches (Kupiec, 1993; Feng, 2004)</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="that mine" comments="">, by mining</edit>
        <text>external signals from a large corpus, such as</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="the" comments=""></edit>
        <text>parenthetical translation “成龙 (Jackie Chan)”,</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="are suited" comments="">complementary</edit>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="to addressing" comments=""></edit>
        <text>the problem</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="associated with" comments="">of</edit>
        <text>ransliteration-based approaches, but the coverage of</text>
        <edit type="word choice;consistency" crr="these approaches" comments="">this approach</edit>
        <text>is limited to popular entities with</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="this type of" comments="">such</edit>
        <text>evidence.</text>
        <text>\n\n The most effective known approach to NE translation has been a holistic framework (You et al., 2010; Kim et al., 2011; You et al., 2012) combining transliteration- and corpus-based methods.</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="These approaches" comments="">In these approaches</edit>
        <edit type="word order;word choice" crr="can address both 1) arbitrary translations and 2) lesser-known entities" comments="">, both 1) arbitrary translations and 2) lesser-known entities can be handled, </edit>
        <text>by propagating the translation scores of known entities to lesser-known entities if they co-occur frequently in both corpora. For example,</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="the" comments="">a</edit>
        <text>lesser-known entity Tom Watson can be translated if Mandelson and Tom Watson co-occur frequently in an English corpus, and their Chinese translations also co-occur frequently in a Chinese corpus, i.e., if the co-occurrences in the two corpora are</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="“symmetric.”" comments="">“symmetric”.</edit>
        <text>\n\n A research question we ask in this paper is</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="the following" comments="added for grammatical correctness; you need a complete clause before a colon"></edit>
        <text>: What if comparable corpora are not comparable enough to support this symmetry assumption? We</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="found" comments="">find</edit>
        <text>that this is indeed the case. For example, even English and Chinese news</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="content created by" comments="">from</edit>
        <text>the same publisher may have a different focus – the Chinese version</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="may focus" comments="">focuses</edit>
        <text>more on Chinese Olympic teams and Chinese local news. In the presence of such asymmetry, all previous approaches</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="">,</edit>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="that build on" comments="">building upon</edit>
        <text>symmetry</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="">,</edit>
        <text>quickly deteriorate</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="through propagation of" comments="">by propagating</edit>
        <text>false positives. For example,</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="the" comments=""></edit>
        <text>co-occurrence of Mandelson and Tom Watson may not appear in a Chinese corpus, which may lead to the translation of Tom Watson into another Chinese entity Gordon Brown which happens to co-occur</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="in" comments="">with</edit>
        <text>the Chinese translation of Mandelson.</text>
        <text>\n\n Our key contribution is</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="devising an approach that can be used" comments=""></edit>
        <text>to avoid such false propagation</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="">,</edit>
        <text>by discerning the semantics of the relations. For example, relations between Mandelson and Tom Watson</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="">,</edit>
        <text>should be semantically different</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="than" comments="">from</edit>
        <text>Chinese relations between ‘戈登·布朗’ (Gordon Brown) and ‘曼德尔森’ (Mandelson). A naive approach would</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="involve" comments="">be</edit>
        <text>finding documents with a similar topic</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="," comments=""></edit>
        <text>such as politics</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="or" comments="">, and</edit>
        <text>scientific discovery, and allowing propagation only when the topic agrees. However, we</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="find" comments="word choice; present tense is better here">found</edit>
        <text>hat a topic is a unit that is too coarse for this task because most articles on Mandelson will invariably fall into the same topic . In clear contrast, we selectively propagate seed translations, only when the relations in the two corpora share the same semantics.</text>
        <text>\n\n This selective propagation can be especially effective for translating challenging types of entities such as organizations, including the WTO</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr=", which are" comments=""></edit>
        <text>used with and without abbreviation in both languages.  Applying a holistic approach (You et al., 2012)</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="to" comments="">on</edit>
        <text>organizations</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="had been shown to" comments=""></edit>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="leads" comments="">lead</edit>
        <text>to poor results (0.06 in terms of the F1-score). A naive approach to</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="increasing" comments="">increase</edit>
        <text>the precision would be to consider multitype co-occurrences</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="in the hope" comments="">hoping</edit>
        <text>that highly precise translations of some type, e.g., persons with an F1-score of 0.69 (You et al., 2012),</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="could" comments="">can</edit>
        <text>be propagated to boost the precision </text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="when translating" comments="">on</edit>                                                                     
        <text>organizations. In our experiments, this naive multi-type propagation still leads to an unsatisfactory F1-score of 0.12.</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="Achieving a score this low" comments="">Such a low score</edit> 
        <text>can be explained</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="using" comments="">by</edit> 
        <text>the following example. When translating ‘WTO’ using the co-occurrence with ‘Mandelson’, other co-occurrences such as (London, Mandelson) and (EU, Mandelson) produce a lot of noise because the right translation of WTO does not share much phonetic/semantic similarity. Our understanding of relation semantics can distinguish “Mandelson was born in London” from “Mandelson visited the WTO” to</text>
        <edit type="style" crr="prevent" comments="">stop</edit>
        <text>false propagations</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr=";" comments="">,</edit>                                                                     
        <edit type="clarity" crr="this method" comments="">which</edit> 
        <text>generates an F1-score 0.25 higher than the existing approaches.</text>
        <text>\n\n More formally, we enable selective propagation of seed translations on weakly comparable corpora by 1) clarifying the detailed meaning of relational information of co-occurring entities and 2) identifying the contexts of the relational information using statement-level context comparison. In other words, we propagate the translation score of a known translation pair to a</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="neighboring" comments="">neighbor</edit> 
        <text>pair if the semantics of their relations in English and Chinese corpora are equivalent</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="in order" comments=""></edit>                                                                     
        <text>to accurately propagate the scores. For example, if we know ‘Russia’→‘俄罗斯’(1) and join→加入(2), then from a pair of statements “Russia(1) joins(2) the WTO(3)” and “俄罗斯(1) 加入(2) 世贸组织(3)”, we can propagate the translation score of (Russia, 俄罗斯)(1) to (WTO, 世贸组织)(3). However, we do not exploit a pair of statements “Russia joined the WTO” and “俄罗斯 谴责(2’) 摩洛哥” because 谴责(2’) does not mean join(2).</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="Additionally" comments="">Furthermore</edit> 
        <text>, we mine a similar English-Chinese document pair that can be found by comparing</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="" comments="">the</edit> 
        <text>entity relationships, such as “Mandelson visited Moscow” and “Mandelson met Alexei Kudrin”, within the English</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="and Chinese documents" comments="">document and the Chinese document</edit> 
        <text>to leverage similar contexts</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="in order" comments=""></edit>                                                                     
        <text>to assure that we use symmetric parts.</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="To achieve" comments="">For</edit> 
        <text>this goal, we first extract relations among entities in documents, such as visit and join, and mine semantically equivalent relations across the languages, e.g., for English and Chinese</text>
        <edit type="readability" crr="we consider" comments="">, such as</edit> 
        <text>join→加入. Once these relation translations are mined, similar document pairs can be identified by comparing each constituent relationship among entities using their relations. Knowing document similarity improves NE translation, and improved NE translation can boost the accuracy of document and relationship similarity. This iterative process can</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="be continued" comments="">continue</edit> 
        <text>until convergence</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="is reached." comments="">.</edit>
        <text>\n\n To the best of our knowledge, our approach is the first to translate a broad range of multilingual relations and exploit them to enhance NE translation. In particular, our approach leverages semantically similar document pairs to exclude incomparable parts that appear</text>
        <edit type="word order" crr="only  in one language." comments="">in one language only.</edit> 
        <text>Our method outperforms</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="previously proposed approaches for" comments="">the previous approaches in</edit>
        <text>translating NE</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="by" comments=""></edit> 
        <text>up to 0.16 in terms of the mean reciprocal rank (MRR) for organization names. Moreover, our method shows robustness, with</text>
        <edit type="word order" crr="an MRR 0.14 higher" comments="">0.14 higher MRR</edit>                                                                     
        <text>than seed translations, on less comparable corpora.</text>                                                 
    </introduction>   
</doc>