<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc id="P15-2023" editor="A" format="Conf" position="S" region="NN">
    <title>
        <text>Discriminative Preordering Meets Kendall's τ Maximization</text>
    </title>
    <abstract>
        <text>This paper explores a simple discriminative preordering model for statistical machine translation. Our model traverses binary constituent trees</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="punctuation - comma not appropriate here because what follows the conjunction is not a full sentence">,</edit>
        <text>and classifies whether children of each node should be reordered. The model itself is not extremely novel, but herein we introduce a new procedure to determine oracle labels so as to maximize Kendall's τ. Experiments in Japanese-to-English translation revealed that </text>
        <edit type="readability;clarity" crr="the translation accuracy of our simple method is comparable with or superior to that of state-of-the-art methods." comments="readability / clarity - moving this earlier makes it clearer earlier what metric we're using and it reads better - the phrase at the end didn't work well.">our simple method is comparable with or superior to that of state-of-the-art methods in translation accuracy.</edit>
    </abstract>   
    <introduction>
        <text>Current statistical machine translation systems suffer from major accuracy degradation in distant languages, primarily because they utilize exceptionally dissimilar word orders. One promising solution to this problem is preordering, in which source sentences are reordered to resemble the target language word orders, after which statistical machine translation is applied to</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="the" comments="grammar - need an article here"></edit>
        <text>reordered sentences (Xia and McCord, 2004; Collins et al., 2005). This is particularly effective for distant language pairs such as English and Japanese (Isozaki et al., 2010b).</text>
        <text>\\ Among such preordering, one of the simplest and straightforward</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="models" comments="grammar - 'one of the' requires plural">model</edit>
        <text>is a discriminative preordering model (Li et al., 2007), which</text>
        <edit type="readability" crr=", given binary trees, classifies whether children of each constituent node should be reordered." comments="readability - this is awkward hanging at the end and it's not entirely clear what it ties to.">classifies whether children of each constituent node should be reordered, given binary trees.</edit>
        <text>This simple model</text>
        <edit type="readability" crr=", however, has" comments="readability - sentence flows better without splitting the verb and object">has, however,</edit>
        <text>difficulty</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="finding" comments="word choice - this is more natural English">to find</edit>
        <text>oracle labels. Yang et al. (2012) proposed a method to approximate oracle labels along dependency trees.</text>
        <text>\\ The present paper proposes a new procedure to find oracle labels. The main idea is simple: we determine reordering decisions in a way that maximizes Kendall's τ of word alignments. We prove that our procedure guarantees the optimal solution for word alignments given as an integer list</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="punctuation - semicolon doesn't belong here.">;</edit>
        <text>in a way that local decisions on each node reach the global maximization of Kendall's τ in total. Any reordering methods that utilize word alignments along the constituency benefit from this proof.</text>
        <text>\\ Empirical study in Japanese-to-English translation</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="demonstrates" comments="grammar - plural form to agree with singular 'study'">demonstrate</edit>
        <text>that</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr=", in terms of translation accuracy," comments="clarity - added based on info from abstract, would need to review rest of paper to verify this is accurate. We need to specify the performance metric we're using."></edit>
        <text>our simple method outperforms a rule-based preordering method and is comparable with or superior to state-of-the-art methods that rely on language-specific heuristics.</text>
        <text>\\ Our contributions are summarized as follows:</text>
        <text>\ We define a method for obtaining oracle labels in discriminative preordering</text>
        <edit type="readability" crr="which maximizes" comments="readability - original was a bit awkward">as the maximization of</edit>
        <text>Kendall's τ.</text>
        <text>\ We give a theoretical background to Kendall's τ- based reordering for binary constituent trees.</text>
        <text>\ We achieve state-of-the-art accuracy in Japanese-to-English translation with a simple method without language-specific heuristics.</text>
    </introduction>   
</doc>