<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc id="W11-1403" editor="C" format="WS" position="NS" region="NN">
    <title>
        <text>Generating Varied Narrative Probability Exercises</text>
    </title>
    <abstract>
        <text>This paper presents Genpex,</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="which is" comments="Word usage / your construction is correct but the proposed addition is more accurate"></edit>
        <text>a system for automatic generation of narrative probability exercises. Generation of exercises in Genpex is</text>
        <edit type="style" crr="achieved in" comments="">done in</edit>
        <text>two steps. First, the system creates a specification of a solvable probability problem</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="which is" comments="Word usage / your construction is correct but the proposed addition is more accurate">,</edit>
        <text>based on input from the user (a researcher or test developer) who selects both a specific question type and a narrative context for that problem. Then, a text expressing the probability problem is generated. The user can tune the generated text by setting the values of</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="several" comments="Word choice / proposed alternative is more accurate">some</edit>
        <text>linguistic variation parameters. By varying the mathematical content of the exercise, its narrative context, and the linguistic parameter settings, many different exercises can be produced. Here, we focus on the natural language generation part of Genpex. After describing how the system works, we then briefly present our first evaluation results, and</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="finally conclude with a" comments="Vocabulary / insert to amplify description of sequence"></edit>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="discussion of a number o" comments="Register / 'some' is correct, but the proposed alternative is more precise">discuss some</edit>
        <text>aspects requiring further investigation.</text>
    </abstract>   
    <introduction>
        <text>Narrative exercises (also called word problems or story problems) are mathematical exercises</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="that are" comments="Word choice / insert to amplify meaning"></edit>
        <text>embedded in a story or text. They are commonly used as test items</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="in order" comments="Word choice / insert to amplify meaning">,</edit>
        <text>to assess or train a student's understanding of the underlying mathematical concepts. When solving a narrative exercise, the student is first required to derive the underlying mathematical question from the story and then to calculate the correct answer to this mathematical problem.</text>
        <text>\\ This paper presents Genpex, which is a system for generating narrative exercises for expressing probability problems. Genpex was created in the context of an international project on item generation for testing student competencies in solving probability problems. Automatic item generation is an effective way of constructing many items with controlled difficulties, based on a set of predefined task parameters (Enright et al., 2002; Deane and Sheehan, 2003; Arendasy et al., 2006; Holling et al., 2009). The goal of our item generation project is to develop a model to support optimal problem and test construction. A large collection of narrative exercises is</text>
        <edit type="style" crr="required" comments="Register / your word is correct, but the proposed alternative is better in academic text">needed</edit>
        <text>in order to test the developed models in field trials. All of these narrative exercises should be different, but the properties that define the difficulty of</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="each" comments="Grammar / you've made reference to several exercises in the first clause, so the second clause should agree with 'each' or 'every'">the</edit>
        <text>exercise should be known. Genpex was designed to enable easy creation of new exercises that meet these requirements.</text>
        <text>\\ Figure 1 shows a narrative probability exercise generated by Genpex.</text>
        <edit type="flow;readability" crr="Since the target group of our project are German high school students, the text of the exercise is in German." comments="Sentence construction / should follow sequence to make reading easier">The text of the exercise is in German, because the target group of our project are German high school students.</edit>
        <text>The texts produced by Genpex are based on a set of example narrative exercises that were created earlier within the project (Zeuch, In preparation).</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="\\ One specific" comments="Word choice / your usage is correct, but the proposed alternative is more precise">\\ A</edit>
        <text>property that sets Genpex apart from other narrative exercise-generation systems is that it was specifically designed to support variation</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="across" comments="Word choice / 'in' is correct, but the proposed alternative is more accurate">in</edit>
        <text>the generated exercises. Unlike other systems, it not only changes the context of the narrative exercise (e.g., instead of bikes, the example exercise could also have been about hotel rooms with different properties) but it also varies the way those texts are formulated. Most existing systems for narrative exercise generation use fixed sentence templates to express mathematical content</text>
        <edit type="readability" crr=". This" comments="Readability / start new sentence">, which</edit>
        <text>means that the same content is always expressed in the same way (Fairon and Williamson, 2002; Arendasy et al., 2006; Holling et al., 2009). A system that uses a linguistically sophisticated approach</text>
        <edit type="flow;readability" crr="(and thereby allows for similar text variations as Genpex)" comments="Readability / sentence is cumbersome. Consider adding parenthesis as proposed to make the flow easier">thus in principle allowing for similar text variations as Genpex,</edit>
        <text>is ModelCreator (Deane and Sheehan, 2003; Higgins et al., 2005). However, this system focuses on semantic factors influencing the expression of events with different participants (e.g., different types of vehicles) rather than on generating linguistic variations.</text>
        <text>\\ Below, we first describe how a probability problem is constructed by Genpex, based on input by the user. Then, we explain in</text>
        <edit type="word choice;redundancy" crr="" comments="Word choice / word not required as it detracts from the meaning of 'detail' (i.e. 'some detail' can potentially mean 'not a lot of detail)">some</edit>
        <text>detail how the natural language generation (NLG) module of Genpex creates a text expressing the probability problem, focusing on the creation of variation in the generated texts. We end with a brief discussion of our</text>
        <edit type="style" crr="initial" comments="Register / proposed alternative is better for academic text">first</edit>
        <text>evaluation results and</text>
        <edit type="clarity" crr="highlight" comments=""></edit>
        <text>some</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="key areas" comments="Word choice / slightly ambiguous">pointers</edit>
        <text>to future work</text>
    </introduction>   
</doc>