<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc id="W11-1403" editor="B" format="WS" position="NS" region="NN">
    <title>
        <text>Generating Varied Narrative Probability Exercises</text>
    </title>
    <abstract>
        <text>This paper presents Genpex, a system for automatic generation of narrative probability exercises. Generation of exercises in Genpex is done in two steps. First, the system creates a specification of a solvable probability problem</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="comma not necessary" comments="">,</edit>
        <text>based on input from the user (a researcher or test developer)</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="," comments=""></edit>
        <text>who selects a specific question type and a narrative context for the problem. Then</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="comma not necessary">,</edit>
        <text>a text expressing the probability problem is generated. The user can tune the generated text by setting the values of some linguistic variation parameters. By varying the mathematical content of the exercise, its narrative context, and the linguistic parameter settings, many different exercises can be produced. Here we focus on the natural language generation</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="aspect" comments="word choice; adding a word with more finesse.">part</edit>
        <text>of Genpex. After describing how the system works, we briefly present our first evaluation results</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="comma not necessary">,</edit>
        <text>and discuss some aspects requiring further investigation.</text>
    </abstract>   
    <introduction>
        <text>Narrative exercises</text>
        <edit type="redundancy" crr="(also called word or story problems)" comments="not necessary to use the same word twice for both concepts">(also called word problems or story problems)</edit>
        <text>are mathematical exercises embedded in a story or text. They are commonly used as test items</text>
        <edit type="punctuation" crr="" comments="comma not necessary">,</edit>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="to train students or assess their" comments="">to assess or train a student's</edit>
        <text>understanding of the underlying mathematical concepts. When solving a narrative exercise, the student is required to derive the underlying mathematical question from the story and</text>
        <edit type="redundancy" crr="calculate the correct answer." comments="extraneous">to calculate the correct answer to this mathematical problem.</edit>
        <text>\\ This paper presents Genpex, a system for generating narrative exercises</text>
        <edit type="clarity;word choice" crr="that express" comments="added for clarity; word choice">expressing</edit>
        <text>probability problems. Genpex was created in the context of an international project on item generation</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="to test" comments="">for testing</edit>
        <text>student competencies in solving probability problems. Automatic item generation is an effective way of constructing many items with controlled difficulties, based on a set of predefined task parameters (Enright et al., 2002; Deane and Sheehan, 2003; Arendasy et al., 2006; Holling et al., 2009). The goal of our item generation project is to develop a model to support optimal problem and test construction. A large collection of narrative exercises is needed to test</text>
        <edit type="word order" crr=" models developed" comments="word order; in this case, I'm assuming they mean testing models in general">the developed models</edit>
        <text>in field trials. All of these narrative exercises should be different, but the properties that define the difficulty of the exercise should be known. Genpex was designed to enable easy creation of new exercises</text>
        <edit type="clarity;word choice" crr="the meet" comments="">meeting</edit>
        <text>these requirements.</text>
        <text>\\ Figure 1 shows a narrative probability exercise generated by Genpex. The text of the exercise is in German, because the target group of our project</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="is" comments="">are</edit>
        <text>German high school students. The texts produced by Genpex are based on a set of example narrative exercises that were created earlier</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="in" comments="">with</edit>
        <text>the project</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="(Zeuch, in preparation). " comments="">(Zeuch, In preparation). </edit>
        <text>\\ A property that sets Genpex apart from other narrative exercise generation systems is that it was specifically designed to support variation in the generated exercises. Unlike other systems, it not only changes the context of the narrative exercise (e.g., instead of bikes, the example exercise could also</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="describe" comments="">have been about</edit>
        <text>hotel rooms with different properties)</text>
        <edit type="readability" crr=", but also" comments="">but it also</edit>
        <text>varies the way the texts are formulated. Most existing systems for narrative exercise generation use fixed sentence templates to express mathematical content, which means that the same content is always expressed in the same way (Fairon and Williamson, 2002; Arendasy et al., 2006; Holling et al., 2009).</text>
        <edit type="flow;clarity" crr="ModelCreator (Deane and Sheehan, 2003; Higgins et al., 2005) is a ystem that uses a linguistically sophisticated approach, thus in principle allowing for text variations similar to those created by Genpex." comments="">A system that uses a linguistically sophisticated approach, thus in principle allowing for similar text variations as Genpex, is ModelCreator (Deane and Sheehan, 2003; Higgins et al., 2005).</edit>
        <text> However, this system focuses on semantic factors influencing the expression of events with different participants (e.g., different types of vehicles) rather than</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="" comments="">on</edit>
        <text>generating linguistic variations.</text>
        <text>\\ Below, we first describe how a probability problem is constructed by Genpex, based on input</text>
        <edit type="grammar" crr="from" comments="">by</edit>
        <text>the user.</text>
        <edit type="word order" crr="We then" comments="">Then we</edit>
        <text>explain in some detail how</text>
        <edit type="word order" crr="Genpex's natural language generation (NLG) module" comments="">natural language generation (NLG) module of Genpex</edit>
        <text>creates a text expressing the probability problem, focusing on the creation of variation in the generated texts. We</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="conclude" comments="">end</edit>
        <text>with a brief discussion of</text>
        <edit type="word order" crr="the results of our first evaluation" comments="">our first evaluation results</edit>
        <text>and some</text>
        <edit type="word choice" crr="directions for" comments="">pointers to</edit>
        <text>future work.</text>
    </introduction>   
</doc>